GURKANWALJOT SINGH BRAR

- @ GURKANWALJOT02@GMAIL.COM
- h 672-515-6120
- a 31550 RIDGEVIEW DRIVE, ABBOTSFORD, BC V2T 6R9

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Skilled student with a diploma in Computer Information Systems and a myriad of experience in customer service with an immense passion for information and technology (IT). Highly organized, with excellent attention to detail to help succeed in any task. Committed to learn and gain new experiences with a keenness to explore new job opportunities in a growth-oriented organization.

EDUCATION

University of Fraser Valley Abbotsford, BC • 2021 - 2022 Diploma: Computer Information Systems

Saint Fateh Singh Punjab, India • 2018 - 2020 Secondary Education (11th and 12th grade)

St. Xavier School -Punjab, India|2015- 2018 High School Diploma (8 -10th grade)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LANGUAGES

- HTML/CSS
- SQL
- PHPJava
- JavaScript
- Python

OTHER SKILLS

- Cybersecurity
- System Administration
- Network Security
- Data SecurityTechnical Support
- System Analysis and Design
- Relational Databases

IT RELEVANT PROJECTS

- HTML Website Project: Created a modern and professional website in support of the Indian Farmers Protest using HTML3 and CSS coding which provided an insight of the protest that took place in India and globally.
- Python Assignments: Made a python program to help calculate employees' taxable incomes, net income and average income of all employees as needed. Also developed a program that took data (i,e., serial number, names, address, sex, date of birth, gross incomes, etc.)from a JavaScript file about the working people of a province and calculated the province average gross income and their net income
- PHP Project: Created a job posting website where students who are looking for jobs could fill their credentials and their resumes for to apply for a job which is displayed on the website. Also, employers could post their job postings on the website and could review the credentials that students have submitted in their job application. Website has been developed using HTML and CSS3 functions. To store the information provided by the students and employees, a database has been created having various tables for storing login information, student profile, employer profile, job description, job application forms etc., using PHP.
- JAVA Project: Made a 2D java game in which player moves inside the maze to find items like energy drink and fruits, which boosts the points that player gets at the start of the game to fight against enemies like wizard, demon, and witch. These enemies are designed to reduce the points of the player. Also, these enemies are placed randomly inside the maze and are not visible to the player. Player moves around the maze to collect the items boosting their points and stops at the point where it is stroked by an enemy. If the player has more points than enemy, then it wins the game, otherwise he would lose against the enemy.

Commented [GB2]: Include skills demonstration in description

Commented [GB1]: Sub-headings for technical skills i.e., languages

GURKANWALJOT SINGH BRAR

- @ GURKANWALJOT02@GMAIL.COM
- h 672-515-9760
- a 31550 RIDGEVIEW DRIVE, ABBOTSFORD, BC V2T 6R9

SOFT SKILLS

- Client-Service Excellence
- Organizational Skills
- Excellent time-management and leadership skills
- Ability to multi-task
- Excellent communication skills
- Excellent teamwork skills
- Critical thinking

REFERENCES

Available Upon Request

WORK HISTORY

Costco Wholesale - Meat Wrapper

- Abbotsford, BC 09/2021 Present
- Wrapping, labelling and stocking meat in an organized manner to ensure high-quality and ease of access for customers
- Demonstrated excellent customer service skills by helping customers whenever they face any issues and providing the best possible solution to achieve customer satisfaction
- Cleaned SOP in the meat department during closing, while adhering to company policies and guidelines by working well with all members of my team

Winners and HomeSense - Store Associate

Abbotsford, BC • 05/2021 - 09/2021

- Greeting customers, responding to questions, improving engagement with merchandise, providing customer service and increasing store sales
- Maintaining an orderly appearance throughout the sales floor and directing customers to merchandise within the store
- Operating on cash registers by managing transactions
- Maintaining safe and clean environment in the warehouse, unpacking boxes, pulling materials to the sales floor; complying with procedures, rules, and regulations

Brills IELTS Coaching Centre - IELTS Tutor

Bathinda, Punjab, IN • 07/2020 - 02/2021

- Motivated students towards learning and studying to build selfconfidence and reduce fear of failure
- Provided homework assistance using specific curriculum and materials
- Improved test scores by focusing on reading comprehension, listening and speaking skills through one-on-one tutoring sessions

Saint Xavier Senior Secondary School - Volunteer Student Council Member

Bathinda, Punjab, IN • 04/2017 - 02/2018

- Oversaw daily administrative operations, including organizing meetings and events
- Followed all school and classroom policies, regulations, dress codes and schedules
- Supported engaging fun and smooth-running events by helping with the organization and planning of the event